Today's video is on Insurance [ __ ] Guaranteed
Savings Schemes.  Savings and that too
guaranteed is the most important part of everyone's life.
With such savings we can breathe a
sigh of relief and sleep peacefully.
And these savings, when combined with insurance, are
100% guaranteed
and totally tax-free up to a certain amount of annual
premium.
When you keep money in savings or FD in banks
, whether it is Rs 10 lakh, 20 lakh
or crores.  If your bank
collapses, your money is safe only up to Rs 5 lakh.
But
whatever amount you invest in Insurance [ __ ] Guaranteed Savings Schemes,
it is 100% safe for your entire policy term
and income period.
Insurance Regulatory and
Development Authority of India (IRDAI), the authority that regulates insurance companies,
requires insurance companies to
maintain a solvency ratio of at least 150%
so that the company can easily repay its liabilities, i.e., the
money it has taken from the policyholders,
and the
policyholders can remain protected.
In simple words, it means that if the liabilities of the company
are 100% then it will have to
keep minimum 150% of the assets or money with IRDAI.
So due to this the money of the policy holders is
100% safe.  So with this type of
insurance [ __ ] guaranteed savings scheme,
our worries are over because we are going to get it anyway.  no matter what happen.
Hello
friends, welcome to On Point Financial Services.
I have made many videos on
life insurance products and ULIP Plus of Tata AI company and some other companies.
So you
must check them out.  You will find the link to my channel's playlist
in the description.  Today
I am going to compare the insurance [ __ ] guaranteed savings products of two companies.
So watch the entire video carefully.  Those
two companies are ICICI Pro and Tata AI.
I will compare ICICI Pro's Gift Pro with
Tata AI's Fortune Guarantee Plus.
Both of these are insurance [ __ ] guaranteed savings
schemes.  So let us now see which one
gives us better returns.  Now we will
understand with an example, suppose we are
considering this product for a 35 years old male who will pay an annual premium of Rs 1
lakh for 10 years.  So he will pay Rs 10 lakh in installments of Rs
1 lakh for 10 years and he will
also get money back guarantee.  That means that
whatever premiums he has paid, Rs. 10
lakh, will be returned to him at the end of the policy term
in both the products.
So with this criteria, now we understand
which product gives how much benefit to him.
So the first benefit in this
is life cover.  ICICI Pro's Gift Pro
offers life cover of 10.7 lakhs for 11
years.  And Tata AI's Fortune Guarantee Plus will have
life cover at ₹1 lakh for 12 years.
So there is a slight difference between the two.  Here
you are getting life cover for 11 years
and here you are getting it for 12 years
and the cover is also a little higher which is
₹1 lax.  Now both these products have a
defeasibility period of 2 years.  That
means you will do this for 10 years at one lakh
and then you have to wait for 2 years in between and
then after that your income period starts.
So in Gift Pro you will get income
every year after 2 years deferment period and
that will be Rs
99680 for 30 years.  So you will
get this much income every year for 30 years and if you see the same income
in Tata's Fortune Guarantee Plus,
it will be Rs
12320. You will get this amount every year for
30 years.  So here you can clearly see
that there is a slight difference in the amount and
in both the products, you get back your paid premium of ₹1 lakh at the end of
the policy term.
So in ICICI Proof, when you pay Rs 10 lakh, the
amount you get
is Rs
39400. This amount also includes your premium of Rs 1 lakh
which you get back.
And in Tata AI A's Fortune
Guarantee Plus, you pay ₹1 lakh and
get ₹
4069600 and in this amount also your
premium of ₹1 lakh is already included which
you get back at the end of the policy term.
Now if we
see the difference in these amounts of Gift Pro and Tata AI, then the
total difference is ₹
79200, so in Fortune Gift Plus
of Tata company, you are getting almost around ₹80,000
more.  So if you want to take this type of plan,
when we compared both of them, we saw that
Tata AI's Fortune Guarantee Plus
gives you better benefits.  But there
is also another version of ICICI Gift Pro
in which you can get increasing income.
We will know about that too.  So in ICICI's
Gift Pro, you get another version,
another option in which if you want, you
can take your income in an increasing way.
So, in this, the guaranteed income that you get
in the increasing income option in the first year will be Rs
68,360 and it will keep increasing every year at a simple interest rate of 5%.
Everything else is the same in it.
But the only difference is that
you will get an increasing income every year by 5%
simple interest.
You will get a little less in the first year because as we
saw in the level income plan, in ICICI Gift
Pro, you
get Rs 99680 every year for 30 years and the
total amount at the end of the policy
term is Rs
39400 but in the increasing income plan, the
company first gives you a little less and
increases it every year with 5% simple interest,
so in the first year you will get an amount of Rs
38360 and then it will increase by 5% every year.
So at the end your final income will be Rs
1667482.  Your final income will increase every year and
become this much.  So
how much are you paying in this?  You are paying 10 lakhs for this.
And at the end of the policy
term, you will get back 100% of your premium amount of Rs 10 lakh.
So its total becomes
4537630, so now this amount has increased and the
reason for this is that in the beginning
you get less income and then it keeps increasing every year
with 5% simple interest.  So
that benefit will be visible to you in overall which is
4537630, so now it is up to you what
type of guaranteed income you would like, whether it is
level income or increasing income.
So we have already seen the level income.
If you want a level income that is the
same income every year and there is no increase in it, then
definitely Tata AI's Fortune
Guarantee Plus is better because in that you are
getting around Rs 80,000 extra.
But if you want increasing income
because you think that my future
expenses may be more, then I want
that I should get this benefit that every year I get a
little more income, then you
can go with this particular option of Gift Pro which
is increasing income and in that,
in the beginning, the amount you get
every year is less and it increases
gradually but overall when you
see, the total amount you will get will be Rs.
4537600
30, so you decide which one
is better for you and you can go with that option.
So I have told you about the
insurance [ __ ] guarantee savings products of both the companies,
you can choose the one which is better for you and my
recommendation is that you should
definitely buy whichever product suits you and
secure yourself and your family and if you
want more information about it then you
can contact me.  I am a financial
consultant and I can
help you understand these products more.
I charge a little consultation fee for that
and if you want to get these products
through me then I
can help you with that too.  And friends if you have
liked my video and the explanation
then please like this video, share it
and also subscribe to my channel.
Thank you so much.  God bless